<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="pretty-atom-feed.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>Fairwater Brewery</title>
  <subtitle>The home of the Fairwater Brewery</subtitle>
  <link href="https://fairwater-brewery.co.uk/feed/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://fairwater-brewery.co.uk/" />
  <updated>2025-01-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>https://fairwater-brewery.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Bryan Robson</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>First Brew of 2025 - Theakston Old Pecuiler</title>
    <link href="https://fairwater-brewery.co.uk/blog/2025/02/07/First%20brew%20of%202025%20-%20Theakston%20Old%20Pecuiler/" />
    <updated>2025-01-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://fairwater-brewery.co.uk/blog/2025/02/07/First%20brew%20of%202025%20-%20Theakston%20Old%20Pecuiler/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My first brewday of 2025 will be this weekend - probably Sunday, as that looks to have the better weather: my brewery is in a detached garage at the bottom of our garden, and I don&#39;t like to have to walk back and forth in the rain if I can avoid it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recipe is &lt;a href=&quot;https://fairwater-brewery.co.uk/recipes/2025-02-07-theakston-old-pecuiler/&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; for a classic Old Ale: Theakson Old Pecuiler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have brewed a clone of this one before, using the recipe from Graham Wheeler&#39;s &lt;em&gt;Brew Your Own British Real Ale&lt;/em&gt;, but this time it&#39;&#39;s based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.themaltmiller.co.uk/product/theakstons-old-peculier-clone/&quot;&gt;this recipe from The Malt Miller site&lt;/a&gt;. The Wheeler recipe is a very basic grist, just base malt and a bit of crystal and chocolate malt, whereas the MM one is a bit more complex, with wheat to give a bit more body and head retention, and some golden syrup and black treacle, which will add some simply fermentable sugars (though I&#39;m going to use molasses rather than treacle, mainly because I have a jar already!). I&#39;m going to use some bramling cross hops, which I&#39;m hoping will add some blackcurrant notes to the beer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve gone for a smack-pack of &lt;a href=&quot;https://wyeastlab.com/product/west-yorkshire-ale/&quot;&gt;Wyeast 1469 &amp;quot;West Yorkshire Ale&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;, which I&#39;m hoping will suit this beer. I&#39;m not prepared, either in equiment terms, or otherwise, to make a starter from a yeast slope as suggested in the MM recipe, but I wanted to use something a little more interesting than one of the dried standards like S-04, Windsor, or Nottingham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past I&#39;ve often based my water treatment on the Graham Wheeler &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jimsbeerkit.co.uk/water.html&quot;&gt;Liquor Treatment Calculator&lt;/a&gt;, but I&#39;m getting used to the calculator in &lt;a href=&quot;https://beersmith.com/&quot;&gt;BeerSmith3&lt;/a&gt; now, which (I belive) closely matches the suggestions from Martin Brungard&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brunwater.com/&quot;&gt;Bru&#39;n Water&lt;/a&gt;, and has the advantage over the latter of meaning that I don&#39;t need to transfer the details of the salts from the latter to the former. My initial water profile (which is in the .beerxml file for the recipe, even though I don&#39;t render it for the recipe page) is taken as far as possible from the most recent Thames Water &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thameswater.co.uk/help/water-and-waste-help/water-quality/check-your-water-quality#/results/RG53JG&quot;&gt;Water Quality Report&lt;/a&gt;, combined with a reasonable average of the hardness measurements I have taken at the start of every brewday for lots of years (using a Salifert kH Test Kit). I keep meaning to get a &amp;quot;proper&amp;quot; water report done, and if I do so I&#39;ll post the results on this site!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>All the old recipes</title>
    <link href="https://fairwater-brewery.co.uk/blog/2025/01/22/All%20the%20old%20recipes/" />
    <updated>2025-01-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://fairwater-brewery.co.uk/blog/2025/01/22/All%20the%20old%20recipes/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve uploaded all the old .BeerXml files from the original website: they can&lt;br&gt;
be found on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://fairwater-brewery.co.uk/recipelist/page-1/&quot;&gt;recipes&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spot-checking suggests that they&#39;re all working correctly, but please let me&lt;br&gt;
know if any don&#39;t work. (...which reminds me, must add some sort of &amp;quot;contact me&amp;quot; page!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I add any recipe-related blog posts I will add to them!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Welcome back to the brewery...</title>
    <link href="https://fairwater-brewery.co.uk/blog/2025/01/19/welcome-back/" />
    <updated>2025-01-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://fairwater-brewery.co.uk/blog/2025/01/19/welcome-back/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been a while since I mothballed the original Fairwater Brewery site, as I didn&#39;t want to pay for the hosting any more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I never really wanted to lose the site, so finally it is making its way back to life, as a static site created by Eleventy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actual content is to come, so far this is all about getting something up and running that looks ok, and gives me a basis to build on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I doubt I&#39;ll be able to recreate the old posts, but I do still have all the data so I might at least upload all the old beer.xml recipes.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>